<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>development on A Work in Progress</title>
    <link>https://adamschepis.com/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in development on A Work in Progress</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://adamschepis.com/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Heroes and Pit Crews</title>
      <link>https://adamschepis.com/blog/of-heroes-and-pit-crews-bringing-techniques-from-the-surgical-world-to-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamschepis.com/blog/of-heroes-and-pit-crews-bringing-techniques-from-the-surgical-world-to-software/</guid>
      <description>Last night I had the pleasure of going to listen to Atul Gawande  speak about medicine, healthcare, his latest book ( The Checklist Manifesto ), and more generally about making systems, processes, and procedures work as complexity increases beyond the capabilities of the individual.
As a surgeon, researcher, and writer Dr. Gawande has tackled some really difficult problems with regards to reducing deaths as a result of surgery and done an impressive amount of research across many fields (including with Boeing engineers, and people who build skyscrapers) to determine how to deal with complexity in a way that reduces error but also allows members of a team to exercise judgement in the heat of the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Bullish on the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://adamschepis.com/blog/still-bullish-on-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamschepis.com/blog/still-bullish-on-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks we&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed a couple of big outages in the cloud computer world. First there was the downtime on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s EC2 infrastructure , and then this week there was the Blogger outage  on Google&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure. These high profile outages, coupled with the slightly different but orders of magnitude more damaging Playstation Network outage have gotten some people questioning the wisdom of building or moving services into the cloud, including the New York Times .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Adam, and i&#39;m a recovering Singleton addict.</title>
      <link>https://adamschepis.com/blog/im-adam-and-im-a-recovering-singleton-addict/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamschepis.com/blog/im-adam-and-im-a-recovering-singleton-addict/</guid>
      <description>My name is Adam, and i&amp;rsquo;m a recovering Singleton addict. There, i&amp;rsquo;ve said it. I used to use singletons all the time because they make doing some things, like sharing state globally, incredibly convenient. My code was littered with XYZManager classes. The defining trait of these classes was the static GetInstance() method that magically enabled me to get access to that object and its state wherever I wanted!! What a great idea, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity</title>
      <link>https://adamschepis.com/blog/productivity-go-for-the-quick-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamschepis.com/blog/productivity-go-for-the-quick-win/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago my boss and I were talking about bug fixing and how there are some developers who seem to be able to get things done everyday without exception while others seem to get stuck on a single issue for days and then finally get through it and then continue to get work done. I told him about how I try to stay productive and keep myself motivated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Complexity vs. Operational Complexity</title>
      <link>https://adamschepis.com/blog/development-complexity-vs-operational-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://adamschepis.com/blog/development-complexity-vs-operational-complexity/</guid>
      <description>I was discussing some solutions with my co-workers recently and I was advocating for one solution while some of my coworkers were advocating for other solutions. The debate was good natured, but everybody felt strongly about their opinions.
While the technical details of the proposed solutions were very different, I also realized another key difference between the solution I was proposing and one of the solutions that my coworker was fighting hardest for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>