<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>A Work in Progress</title>
    <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content on A Work in Progress</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 09:14:40 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://adamschepis.com/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Being a mentor</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/mentoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 09:14:40 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/mentoring/</guid>
      <description>I have always considered myself a good and willing mentor for younger engineers but I have never been a formal mentor for anyone. Recently I was offered the opporunity to formally mentor a promising younger engineer and I was happy to accept.
After I accepted my first thought was &amp;ldquo;ok, now what am I going to do?&amp;rdquo; I thought back to my earlier days as an engineer and what my mentors taught me as well as what I wished I had from a mentor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Best Year Ever</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/best-year-ever/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/best-year-ever/</guid>
      <description>Today marks my 1 year anniversary at CloudHealth Technologies . This last year has been a whirlwind to say the least. While today marks the anniversary of my start date at CloudHealth the story actually begins several months earlier.
In 2014 I was working at Springboard Retail  who, I might add, are doing some awesome things in the retail space. On June 24, 2014 I got a message on Stack Overflow Careers  from a guy named Joe Kinsella  wondering if I might be interested in exploring opportunities at his startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Don&#39;t be a 10x developer</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/don-t-be-a-10x-developer-be-a-force-multiplier/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/don-t-be-a-10x-developer-be-a-force-multiplier/</guid>
      <description>CloudHealth  is growing really fast and on the engineering team we have reached the size where we are starting to bring in more junior developers. For us this means developers who have great talent and ability but are just out of school or recently out of school. I like to say that these girls and guys have horsepower.
Junior developers are not a blank slate, but they are about as close as you get in our industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Gloves are Off</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/the-gloves-are-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/the-gloves-are-off/</guid>
      <description>This morning at CloudHealth  we had the best sprint retrospective we&amp;rsquo;ve had during my entire tenure (5 months already!?) Let me tell you why.
The sprint itself was really productive. We delivered a lot of value to our customers, we responded promptly to customer issues, and we moved ourselves forward strategically. That being said, no codebase, process, product, or engineer is perfect. We&amp;rsquo;ve all go our strengths, weaknesses, tendencies, and pet peeves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeping Pace</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/keeping-pace/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/keeping-pace/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been at my new job at CloudHealth Technologies  for about two months now. I feel incredibly grateful to be able to work with such a talented team and to have the opportunity to tackle hard problems in an increasingly interesting space. Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve learned a few things over the past 60 days now that i&amp;rsquo;ve switched from being a consumer of cloud services to a provider of value on top of cloud services.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Heroku addon SSO in Rails using Devise</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/heroku-addon-sso-in-rails-using-devise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/heroku-addon-sso-in-rails-using-devise/</guid>
      <description>I was going through the process of integrating Heroku  SSO with the addon I am developing and although it was pretty straightforward I was surprised that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find an existing gem that would add this functionality to Devise .
Once I had it all working in my rails app via a custom Warden strategy I decided that I would extract it into a Rails engine and commit it to Github so that maybe others can use it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Go Home</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/why-i-go-home-a-dads-manifesto/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/why-i-go-home-a-dads-manifesto/</guid>
      <description>TL;DR I love my job, I love my career, I love solving hard problems, and I love crafting great software. Just not as much as a I love my daughter.
When I was younger, i was one of the developers who would get to work early, code all day, leave the office after everybody else, and then get back online and code at night. It didn&amp;rsquo;t matter what I was coding on, I just wanted to be coding.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Break the Build!</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/break-the-build/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/break-the-build/</guid>
      <description>The Scream Doll &amp;ndash; Our token object of shame, given to build breakers.  I was just having a conversation with a colleague and he was telling me about how the bug count on one of our projects skyrocketed overnight (during the last week of a cycle) because QA finally looked at the output of our static analysis (Java findbugs) and logged defects on all the medium and high priority errors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drinking from a Firehose</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/drinking-from-a-firehose/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/drinking-from-a-firehose/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I interview a person for an open position I always ask the person how they keep up-to-date and keep their knowledge set relevant with industry trends and new technologies. The answer can tell you a lot about the person across the table from you, and the beauty of the question is that it gives you lots of opportunity for follow-up questions so its easy to determine if the candidate is being honest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Of Heroes and Pit Crews</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/of-heroes-and-pit-crews-bringing-techniques-from-the-surgical-world-to-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/of-heroes-and-pit-crews-bringing-techniques-from-the-surgical-world-to-software/</guid>
      <description>Last night I had the pleasure of going to listen to Atul Gawande  speak about medicine, healthcare, his latest book ( The Checklist Manifesto ), and more generally about making systems, processes, and procedures work as complexity increases beyond the capabilities of the individual.
As a surgeon, researcher, and writer Dr. Gawande has tackled some really difficult problems with regards to reducing deaths as a result of surgery and done an impressive amount of research across many fields (including with Boeing engineers, and people who build skyscrapers) to determine how to deal with complexity in a way that reduces error but also allows members of a team to exercise judgement in the heat of the moment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Bullish on the Cloud</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/still-bullish-on-the-cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/still-bullish-on-the-cloud/</guid>
      <description>Over the past few weeks we&amp;rsquo;ve witnessed a couple of big outages in the cloud computer world. First there was the downtime on Amazon&amp;rsquo;s EC2 infrastructure , and then this week there was the Blogger outage  on Google&amp;rsquo;s infrastructure. These high profile outages, coupled with the slightly different but orders of magnitude more damaging Playstation Network outage have gotten some people questioning the wisdom of building or moving services into the cloud, including the New York Times .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;m Adam, and i&#39;m a recovering Singleton addict.</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/im-adam-and-im-a-recovering-singleton-addict/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/im-adam-and-im-a-recovering-singleton-addict/</guid>
      <description>My name is Adam, and i&amp;rsquo;m a recovering Singleton addict. There, i&amp;rsquo;ve said it. I used to use singletons all the time because they make doing some things, like sharing state globally, incredibly convenient. My code was littered with XYZManager classes. The defining trait of these classes was the static GetInstance() method that magically enabled me to get access to that object and its state wherever I wanted!! What a great idea, right?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Productivity</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/productivity-go-for-the-quick-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/productivity-go-for-the-quick-win/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago my boss and I were talking about bug fixing and how there are some developers who seem to be able to get things done everyday without exception while others seem to get stuck on a single issue for days and then finally get through it and then continue to get work done. I told him about how I try to stay productive and keep myself motivated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Development Complexity vs. Operational Complexity</title>
      <link>http://adamschepis.com/blog/development-complexity-vs-operational-complexity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://adamschepis.com/blog/development-complexity-vs-operational-complexity/</guid>
      <description>I was discussing some solutions with my co-workers recently and I was advocating for one solution while some of my coworkers were advocating for other solutions. The debate was good natured, but everybody felt strongly about their opinions.
While the technical details of the proposed solutions were very different, I also realized another key difference between the solution I was proposing and one of the solutions that my coworker was fighting hardest for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>